<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-10-03T01:32:52+03:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">techlanka.lk | எளிய தமிழில் தொழிநுட்ப செய்திகள்</title><subtitle>Latest Technology based news in Tamil</subtitle><entry><title type="html">அலெக்சாவுடன் தமிழில் பேசலாம்! தமிழ் மொழியில் Amazon Alexa</title><link href="/alexa-in-tamil" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="அலெக்சாவுடன் தமிழில் பேசலாம்! தமிழ் மொழியில் Amazon Alexa" /><published>2018-09-18T13:40:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-18T13:40:00+03:00</updated><id>/alexa-in-tamil</id><content type="html" xml:base="/alexa-in-tamil">&lt;p&gt;Alexa gets new skills and now customers in India can help Alexa learn Tamil, Hindi, and other Indian languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;அமேசான் நிறுவனத்தின் மெய்நிகர் உதவியாளரான‌ அலெக்சாவால் இனி தமிழ் மொழியிலும் பதிலளிக்க‌ முடியும். இனி முதல் இந்திய வாடிக்கையாளர்கள், அலெக்சா (Amazon’s digital assistant Alexa) பயன்படுத்தி பல்வேறு இந்திய மொழிகளில் பேச்சு பரிமாற்றம் செய்ய‌ முடியும் என்று தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. செயற்கை அறிவுத்திறனுடன் (artificial intelligence) இயங்கும் அலெக்சா, தற்பொழுது ஆங்கிலத்தில் மட்டுமே பயனர்களுடன் பேச்சில் ஈடுபடுகிறது. ஆப்பிள் இன் சிரி மற்றும் கூகிள் அசிஸ்டண்ட் (Apple’s Siri and Google Assistant) போன்ற மெய்நிகர் உதவியாளர்களுக்கு (virtual assistants ) நிகராக‌ உள்ளது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;தற்போது அமேசான் நிறுவனம், அலெக்சா இன் பேச்சு அறிதலினை மேம்படுத்தும் விதமாய் சில இந்திய மொழிகளில் அலெக்சாவை பயன்படுத்த முடியும் எனும் ஒரு புதிய திறனையும் சேர்த்துள்ளது. குறிப்பாக celo (கிளியோ) தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் கீழ் இந்த அமேசான் அலெக்சாவைப் பயன்படுத்த முடியும். கிளியோ தொழில்நுட்பம், மொழியியலாளர்கள் மற்றும் தரவு விஞ்ஞானிகள் கொண்ட‌ ஒரு குழுவால் வடினமைக்கப்பட்டது. இக்குழு ஏற்கனவே பிரஞ்சு மொழியினை அலெக்சா புரிதலுக்காக‌ மேம்படுத்த உதவியுள்ளது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;மேலும் இந்த அலெக்சா 2017-துவகத்தில், ஆங்கிலம் மட்டுமே புரிந்துதவும் கருவியாக‌ அமெரிக்காவில் அறிமுகம் செய்யப்பட்டது. தற்சமயம் தழிழ், இந்தி, கன்னடம், பெங்காலி, மராட்டி, குஜராத்தி, தெலுங்கு போன்ற மொழிகளில் அறிமுகம் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;அமேசான் எக்கோ (Amazon Echo) ஸ்பீக்கர்கள் மட்டுமின்றி பல மின்னணு சாதனங்களின் துணைகொண்டு குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட மொழிகளில் நீங்கள் அலெக்சாவுடன் மிக எளிமையாக பேச முடியும்.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இப்போது அறிமுகம் செய்யப்பட்ட‌ இந்த புதிய திறனை ஆக்டிவேட் செய்ய அமேசான் எக்கோ ஸ்பீக்கரிடம் அலெக்ஸா ஒப்பன் க்ளியோ (Alexa, open Cleo ) என்று குரல் கட்டளையிட்டால் போதும். பின்பு ஏதேனும் ஒரு மொழியைக் கூறி அதனுடன் மிக எளிமையாக பேசமுடியும்.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mirshad Makeen</name></author><category term="Artificial intelligence" /><summary type="html">Alexa gets new skills and now customers in India can help Alexa learn Tamil, Hindi, and other Indian languages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">இன்டெல் 9வது ஜென். புரோஸசர்கள் (9th generation processors) அக்டோபரில் அறிமுகம்.</title><link href="/launching-9th-generation-processors" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="இன்டெல் 9வது ஜென். புரோஸசர்கள் (9th generation processors) அக்டோபரில் அறிமுகம்." /><published>2018-09-18T13:18:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-18T13:18:00+03:00</updated><id>/launching-9th-generation-processors</id><content type="html" xml:base="/launching-9th-generation-processors">&lt;p&gt;Intel launching its 9th generation processors - new Core i9, i7 and i5 processors on October 1st with 8 cores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இன்டெல் நிறுவத்தின், 8 கோர்களால் ஆன‌ புதிய புரோஸசர்களான‌ கோர் i9, i7 மற்றும் i5 (new Core i9, i7 and i5 processors on October 1st with 8 cores) அக்டோபர் 1 ஆம் தேதி அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட‌ உள்ளன‌. இவை அனைத்தும் 9வது தலைமுறை புரோசசர்களாக‌ வெளியாகவுள்ளன.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இன்டெல் கோர் i9-9900K, 8 கோர்களையும் 16 இழையுடனும் (Intel Core i9-9900K with 8 cores and 16 threads) அறிமுகம் செய்யப்படுகிறது. இணைய‌ தகவல்களின்படி, கோர் i9-9900K, கோர் ஐ9 (தொடரில்) பிராண்டின் கீழ் வெளியாகும் முதல் பிரதான‌ டெஸ்க்டாப் புரோஸசராக‌ (Core i9-9900K will be the first mainstream desktop processor) இருக்கும். இதில் முதன் முறையாக 16MB கொள்ளளவுடைய மூன்றாம் நிலை பதுக்கு நினைவகமும் (L3 Cache Memory) உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Core i7-9700K புரோஸசர் எட்டு கோர்கள் கொண்ட‌ (8 Core) முதல் பிரதான வகை புரோஸசராகும். இதன் வேகமானது 3.6 GHz முதல் 4.9 GHz வரை ஊக்கமளிக்கும் ஆற்றலைக் கொண்டது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;எதிர்வரும் 9000 தொடர் இன்டெல் புரோஸசர்கள் ஏற்கனவே இருக்கும் Z3xx தொடர் மதர்போர்டுகளுடன் இணக்கமாக இருப்பதை பல மதர்போர்டு விற்பனையாளர்கள் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளனர் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Imran Yaseen</name></author><category term="software" /><summary type="html">Intel launching its 9th generation processors - new Core i9, i7 and i5 processors on October 1st with 8 cores.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">வேடிக்கையான டுவீட் பதில்கள், தடை செய்தது டுவிட்டர்!</title><link href="/twitter-blocks-unwanted-replies" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="வேடிக்கையான டுவீட் பதில்கள், தடை செய்தது டுவிட்டர்!" /><published>2018-09-17T15:18:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-17T15:18:00+03:00</updated><id>/twitter-blocks-unwanted-replies</id><content type="html" xml:base="/twitter-blocks-unwanted-replies">&lt;p&gt;Look these funny Twitter responses for a user who killed mosquito and posted it on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;சமீபகாலமாக‌ சமூக வலைத்தளங்கள் (social media) அதன் பயனர்களை துன்புறுத்தல்களில் இருந்து பாதுகாக்கும் முயற்சியை முழுவீச்சில் செயல்படுத்தி வருகின்றது. ஒருவரைப் பற்றி அநாவசிய தவல்களை, குறிப்பிட்ட‌ தகவலினை தவறாக‌ பரப்புதல், பழிவாங்கல்கள் போன்ற‌ பதிவுகளை மிக கவனத்துடன் பரிசீலித்து அவற்றை பிரசுரித்து வருகின்றன.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இதற்கு டுவிட்டர் சமூகவலைத் (Twitter social networking) தளமும் விதிவிலக்கானது அல்ல எனும் எடுத்துக்காட்டாக சில தினங்களுக்கு முன்னர் ஜப்பானிய‌ பயனர் ஒருவரை தடைசெய்துள்ள சம்பவம் நிகழ்ந்துள்ளது,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;குறித்த நபர் கொசு ஒன்றினை கொன்றுவிட்டு அதன் புகைப்படத்தினை டுவிட்டரில் பதிவு (twitter posts) செய்திருந்தார் . அத்துடன் நின்று விடாது அந்த‌ புகைப்படத்திற்கான‌ வாசகத்தில் “நான் ஓய்வாக இருக்கும்போதும், தொலைக்காட்சி பார்க்கும்போதும் தொடர்ந்து என்னை துன்புறுத்திக்கொண்டு இருந்தாய்… அதனால் இறந்து போ”, என டுவீட் செய்திருந்தார்.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ஆங்கிலத்தில் உண்மை வாசகம் : The tweet reads: “Bastard! Where do you get off biting me all over while I’m just trying to relax and watch TV? Die! (Actually you’re already dead).” The tweet was posted alongside a photo of the dead mosquito.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இந்த வேடிக்கையான‌ டுவீட்டினை டுவிட்டரின் செயற்கை அறிவுத்திறன் (தானியங்கி / artificial intelligence) அமைப்பு கண்டுபிடித்து எச்சரிக்கை அறிவித்து கேள்வி எழுப்பி உள்ளது..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ஜப்பானிய பயனரின் (Japanese Twitter user) @nemuismywife எனும் டுவிட்டர் கணக்கு நிறுத்தப்பட்டது (பயனர் தடை). அவர் பின்னர் @DaydreamMatcha எனும் மற்றொரு கணக்கு உருவாக்கினார், ஆனால் ட்விட்டர் அதனையும் பயனரை வினவியபின் முடக்கிவிட்ட‌து.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mirshad Makeen</name></author><category term="Social media" /><summary type="html">Look these funny Twitter responses for a user who killed mosquito and posted it on twitter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Configure Unicenta oPOS with MySQL Database Server.</title><link href="/configuring-unicenta-pos-mysql-database" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configure Unicenta oPOS with MySQL Database Server." /><published>2018-09-10T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/configuring-unicenta-pos-mysql-database</id><content type="html" xml:base="/configuring-unicenta-pos-mysql-database">&lt;h2 id=&quot;unicentas-default-configuration-when-freshly-installed-is-set-to-use-the-derby-database-server-a-database-server-embedded-inside-of-unicenta-this-is-only-good-for-testing-and-experimental-purposes-but-when-youre-ready-to-deploy-your-unicenta-box-you-should-be-using-it-with-an-external-database-server-like-mysql&quot;&gt;Unicenta’s default configuration when freshly installed is set to use the Derby Database Server. A database server embedded inside of Unicenta. This is only good for testing and experimental purposes. But when you’re ready to deploy your Unicenta box, you should be using it with an external Database Server like MySQL.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guide to Unicenta oPOS, that will teach how you would configure or set it up with a MySQL Database Server on MS Windows. It’s a very easy to follow guide and all procedures are written step-by-step with reference images. So if you’re looking for such guide, then jump in to read the rest of the tutorial. You could use this guide for Windows or Linux based installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the main purpose of this guide is to configure Unicenta with MySQL Database Server.
With this kind of setup, your Unicenta terminal should be able to access the database server whether it be online based server or locally deployed within your premises.
The advantages of this are; You have a separate database server where you store all your data and keep them safe in case your Unicenta box or terminal crashed or broke, you could also reinstall Unicenta for as many as you want while keeping your data safe and maintained from the database server, you could setup a multiple Unicenta terminal while maintaining a single database server which unify all your data and configurations and no need for a separate server for each terminal, you could also use a remote or online MySQL database server and connect any Unicenta terminal from different parts of the world and unify them using a single instance of database server, you as ADMIN could remotely login to Unicenta and check transaction logs, total sales and other managerial functions for a store or restaurant.
So for this guide, you’ll be taking advantage of those mentioned above after you successfully configured the MySQL database with Unicenta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To follow this guide, you must have the following.
Requirements
These are the things you need before starting off with this guide.
An instance of Unicenta installation
A separate machine/computer if you want a separate database server.
USB Web Server software for Windows based database server (if you want to use. Windows)
MySQL and LAMP Stack
PuTTy if using Windows for configuration
Some knowledge of Linux
A lot of patience
Note: I’ll be using DB and DBS here to refer to Database and Database Server.
Installation Options
There are different options and setups to configure a Database Server with your POS System.
Some options are:
Option 1 – DBS on the same machine where Unicenta is installed.
Option 2 – DBS on another separate or dedicated machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Option 1: MySQL DBS and Unicenta on the same computer.
Before you start with the initial step, make sure that you already have a working Unicenta instance.
Windows Based
In this part of the guide, we’ll configure a MySQL DBS for a Windows-based Unicenta terminal.
Both Unicenta and MySQL are on the same Windows machine.
Procedures
Step 1 – Download, extract and run USBWebserver.
You know why I recommend this portable software? It’s because I’ve already tried and tested it and had used it several times for test purposes.
But if we’re talking about multiple nodes or terminals, we should use a dedicated machine for the DBS.
To continue, just download the software, extract it to a permanent directory of your choice. Say for instance, Drive D or any drive partition other than drive C:.
Step 2 – Run the software.
Since this software is a portable server, you don’t have to configure or install any additional software, just run it.
Click on the the usbwebserver.exe file, the software should launch.
Now choose your preferred language from the drop-down menu and click OK to continue.
You should see the dashboard now.
Reference Image: USBWebserver Dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3 – Configure MySQL Port.
You may or may not configure this further. But with this software, MySQL is bound to listen to port: 3307 whereas MySQL’s default listening port is 3306.
If you want to change it back to the default port, then configure it from the dashboard.
Click on Settings tab and then change port number under Port MySQL field.
Click save button.
Step 4 – Create a database for Unicenta.
Launch PHPMyAdmin using the dashboard, you could click on the the button or directly access the page using your favorite browser (Firefox or Chrome).
To access the page using a browser, browse to:
http://localhost:8080/phpmyadmin/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then login using root as the username while usbw for the password. You should see a page similar to this image.
Click on Databases menu to create a new DB for Unicenta. Enter a DB name under the Create database field, and then click on the create button. You should now have a DB for your POS. See reference image here.
Now let’s create a new user for the DB. The easiest way to do this is to create a new user with the same name as the DB name.
Click on User from the top navigation menu, then click on the Add user text link. A new page should open, now fill-up the following fields like so.
User Name – unicenta
Host – localhost
Password – your-password
NOTE: if you wanted to have a stronger password, use the Generate password button to create a longer and difficult password. When you click on the button, it will automatically fill the password field, plus it will show you the generated password on a separate field. You should copy and save this password and keep it somewhere safe.
Let’s continue, browse a further down and click/tick:
Create database with same name and grant all privileges
Grant all privileges on wildcard name
Then click Check All text link for the Global Privileges to select all options under this. Finally, click Go button from the bottom-right of the page.
And that’s it! You’ve created a Database for Unicenta. The next step would be to configure Unicenta to connect to the server.
Step 5 – Connect Unicenta to the DBS.
Go to the folder where Unicenta is installed, and then find and click the file configure.bat.
A configuration screen should pop-up like the one shown in this image.
Configure the settings like so;
From the Database dropdown menu, choose MySQL.
For the URL, jdbc:mysql://localhost:3306/unicenta
For User, unicenta
For Passwrd, your-password
Now, click the Test button to test your connection. If all is well, then you should receive a You’re Connected! pop-up message. Reference image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click OK and then finally save the settings. You’re now ready to launch and connect Unicenta to your database.
Step 6 – Fire up Unicenta.
Click on your shortcut to open Unicenta, a pop-up notice saying…
A working database cannot be detected. 
A default database will be created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to continue?
This is not an error, but a notice. It’s just natural that your newly created DB has no tables yet. So you need to hit Continue to create the tables.
Once you clicked OK you should be redirected to your Unicenta screen. If you’ve gotten this far, then congratulations you did it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mirshad Makeen</name></author><category term="softwares" /><category term="software" /><summary type="html">Unicenta’s default configuration when freshly installed is set to use the Derby Database Server. A database server embedded inside of Unicenta. This is only good for testing and experimental purposes. But when you’re ready to deploy your Unicenta box, you should be using it with an external Database Server like MySQL. Guide to Unicenta oPOS, that will teach how you would configure or set it up with a MySQL Database Server on MS Windows. It’s a very easy to follow guide and all procedures are written step-by-step with reference images. So if you’re looking for such guide, then jump in to read the rest of the tutorial. You could use this guide for Windows or Linux based installation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Delegate the domain to Another Name Server</title><link href="/MX-Delegate-the-domain-to-Another-NameServer" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Delegate the domain to Another Name Server" /><published>2018-09-06T13:00:40+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-06T13:00:40+03:00</updated><id>/MX-Delegate-the-domain-to-Another-NameServer</id><content type="html" xml:base="/MX-Delegate-the-domain-to-Another-NameServer">&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-can-delegate-your-lk-domain-to-any-other-name-server-and-take-control-of-your-dns-to-do-this-you-need-to-go-to-the-domain-settings-on-domainslk-site-and-select-the-type-you-need-to-add-to-name-serverchange-the-dns-server-that-supports-the-domainchanging-this-will-result-in-deleting-all-your-existing-resource-records&quot;&gt;You can delegate your LK domain to any other Name server and take control of your DNS. To do this, you need to go to the domain settings on domains.lk site and ‘select the type you need to add’ to Name Server.change the DNS server that supports the domain.(Changing this will result in deleting all your existing Resource Records).&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;you-can-choose-any-of-the-name-server-providers-some-best-known-providers-are-listed-below&quot;&gt;You can choose any of the Name Server Providers, some best known providers are listed below.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare
ClouDNS
DNSMadeEasy
Dyn
Route53
UltraDNS
Verisign
Zoho&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;after-delegating-the-domain&quot;&gt;After delegating the domain:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can manage your domain’s DNS records in your NS service providers DNS editor.
Primary DNS server – “dns1.techlanka.lk.” (The dot in the end is NOT a mistake
Secondary DNS server – “dns2.techlanka.lk.” 
Important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s no compulsory to add more than one DNS server, it depends on your Domain provider.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the delegation settings have a field for entering the IP addresses, leave them empty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait for the changes to take effect in the DNS (this may take up to 24 hours)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;create-a-cname-record-with-specific-content-to-lk-domain&quot;&gt;Create a CNAME record with specific content to LK domain&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In LK domain control panel the way of adding CNAMEs is quite different,
For example, instead of adding the host @ in the Name field, you need yo add ‘techlanka.lk.’ 
same applies for when you add www it should be as ‘www.techlanka.lk.’
Create a new CNAME record with the following field values (the field names may differ for different control panels):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Name – A sub-domain of your domain with the same name as the string shown on the confirmation page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, the confirmation page shows the string “yamail-123456abcdef”, and you want to confirm the domain “techlanka.lk”. In this case, you should set the CNAME record like this,:
“yamail-123456abcdef.techlanka.lk.” (with a dot at the end).
In some control panels, the dot at the end is added automatically, or you don’t need to enter the name of the domain being confirmed. In this case you have adda a dot manually for LK domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Value –
“mail.techlanka.lk.” 
The dot at the end of the server name is required for LK Domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check the CNAME record, click the domain again in the list of domains, then click Check. Keep in mind that it may take up to 24 hours for DNS changes to take effect.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mirshad Makeen</name></author><category term="Getting started" /><summary type="html">You can delegate your LK domain to any other Name server and take control of your DNS. To do this, you need to go to the domain settings on domains.lk site and ‘select the type you need to add’ to Name Server.change the DNS server that supports the domain.(Changing this will result in deleting all your existing Resource Records).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ஜிமெயிலிலும் இப்போது @ உடன் நபர்களைக் குறிப்பிடலாம். ட்விட்டர் போலவே !</title><link href="/gmail-new-feature-@replies" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ஜிமெயிலிலும் இப்போது @ உடன் நபர்களைக் குறிப்பிடலாம். ட்விட்டர் போலவே !" /><published>2018-08-24T16:18:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-08-24T16:18:00+03:00</updated><id>/gmail-new-feature-@replies</id><content type="html" xml:base="/gmail-new-feature-@replies">&lt;p&gt;Now Gmail lets you ‘@’ mention people to link them with their email ID in email’s body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ஜிமெயில் சமீபத்தில் அறிவிக்கப்பட்ட சில அறிவுபூர்ணமான புதுப்பித்தல்கள் புது அம்சங்களைக் கொண்டவை. ஸ்மார்ட் கம்போஸ் மற்றும் உள்வரும் செய்திகளுக்கான உறக்கநிலை பொத்தான் ( Snooze Button) ஆகியன உள்ளன.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;சீரமைக்கப்பட்ட புதிய ஜிமெயிலில், ட்விட்டர் போன்று பயனர்களை ‘@’ பயன்படுத்தி குறிப்பிடும் வசதியும் உள்ளது, தெரியுமா ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gmail இன் புதிய பதிப்பை நீங்கள் பயன்படுத்த வேண்டும். You will have to use Gmail’s newest version. எப்படி பெறுவது என அறிய கிளிக் செய்யவும்&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;நீங்கள் ஒரு புதிய மின்னஞ்சல் அல்லது பதிலை எழுதுகையில் (composing a new Gmail message or a reply,), @ குறியை (@ symbol) உள்ளிட்டதும், உங்களின் காண்டாக்ட் லிஸ்டில் உள்ள நபர்களின் பெயர்களைப் பரிந்துரைக்கும். குறிப்பிட்ட நபரின் பெயரைத் தெரிவு செய்து, அவருக்கான மின்னஞ்சலையும் இணைத்து சேர்த்துக்கொள்ளலாம்.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;உதாரணமாக, @ Clara என டைப் செய்கின்ற போது அந்த பெயருடன் உங்கள் தொடர்பு பட்டியலில் (Gmail Contact List) உள்ள நபர்களின் பட்டியல் ஒன்றைக் கொண்டு வரும். முதற்பெயர் அல்லது கடைப்பெயரினை பரிந்துரைக்கும். இவற்றில் ஒன்றை தேர்ந்தெடுக்கையில், பெயருடன் mailto இணைப்பையும் ஜிமெயில் சேர்க்கும் (will add a mailto link labelled with their name). மின் அஞ்சலைப் பெறும் பெறுநர் அந்த இணைப்பைக் கிளிக் செய்யும் போது, அது புதிய மின் அஞ்சல் தொகுக்கும் விண்டோவினைக் காண்பிக்கும் ( Gmail -&amp;gt;new compose window ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இதன்மூலம் மற்றொருவரை அறிமுகப்படுத்தி தொடர்பு கொள்ள முடியும், அல்லது பல நபர்களின் மின்னஞ்சல் முகவரிகளை விரைவாக ஒரு மின்னஞ்சலில் பட்டியலிட இது உதவும்.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;மேலும் @ குறிக்கு பதிலாக ஒரு + குறியைக் டைப் செய்து நபரினை தேர்ந்தெடுத்தால், அந்தத் தொடர்புடைய நபர் தற்போதைய மெயிலின் பெறுநராக தானாக சேர்க்கப்படுவார்.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mirshad Makeen</name></author><category term="google" /><summary type="html">Now Gmail lets you ‘@’ mention people to link them with their email ID in email’s body.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">தமிழில் ஒரு டெஸ்ட்</title><link href="/test-for" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="தமிழில் ஒரு டெஸ்ட்" /><published>2017-07-27T13:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T13:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/test-for-</id><content type="html" xml:base="/test-for">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We know that first impressions are important, so we’ve populated your new site with some initial &lt;strong&gt;Getting Started&lt;/strong&gt; posts that will help you get familiar with everything in no time. This is the first one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;there-are-a-few-things-that-you-should-know-up-front&quot;&gt;There are a few things that you should know up-front:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ghost is designed for ambitious, professional publishers who want to actively build a business around their content. That’s who it works best for. If you’re using Ghost for some other purpose, that’s fine too - but it might not be the best choice for you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The entire platform can be modified and customized to suit your needs, which is very powerful, but doing so &lt;strong&gt;does&lt;/strong&gt; require some knowledge of code. Ghost is not necessarily a good platform for beginners or people who just want a simple personal blog.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For the best experience we recommend downloading the Ghost Desktop App for your computer, which is the best way to access your Ghost site on a desktop device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ghost is made by an independent non-profit organisation called the Ghost Foundation. We are 100% self funded by revenue from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghost.org/pricing&quot;&gt;Ghost(Pro)&lt;/a&gt; service, and every penny we make is re-invested into funding further development of free, open source technology for modern journalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main thing you’ll want to read about next is probably: &lt;a href=&quot;https://demo.ghost.io/the-editor/&quot;&gt;the Ghost editor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re done reading, you can simply delete the default &lt;strong&gt;Ghost&lt;/strong&gt; user from your team to remove all of these introductory posts!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Imran Yaseen</name></author><category term="android" /><summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to Ghost, it’s great to have you :)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Using the Ghost editor</title><link href="/the-editor" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Using the Ghost editor" /><published>2017-07-27T12:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T12:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/the-editor</id><content type="html" xml:base="/the-editor">&lt;p&gt;Ghost uses a language called &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; to format text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a &lt;strong&gt;?&lt;/strong&gt; icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;formattingtext&quot;&gt;Formatting text&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most common shortcuts are of course, &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt; text, &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; text, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com&quot;&gt;hyperlinks&lt;/a&gt;. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + B&lt;/code&gt; for Bold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + I&lt;/code&gt; for Italic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + K&lt;/code&gt; for a Link&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CMD/Ctrl + H&lt;/code&gt; for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;insertingimages&quot;&gt;Inserting images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Computer&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files &lt;strong&gt;before&lt;/strong&gt; uploading them to Ghost.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;makinglists&quot;&gt;Making lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use &lt;code&gt;*&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt;. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crack the eggs over a bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whisk them together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make an omellete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember to buy milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feed the cat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Come up with idea for next story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;addingquotes&quot;&gt;Adding quotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dividingthingsup&quot;&gt;Dividing things up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping &lt;code&gt;---&lt;/code&gt; on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/advanced-markdown/&quot;&gt;Advanced Markdown Guide&lt;/a&gt; - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of &lt;a href=&quot;/using-tags/&quot;&gt;how to use Ghost tags&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mirshad Makeen</name></author><category term="tips &amp; tricks" /><summary type="html">Ghost uses a language called Markdown to format text. When you go to edit a post and see special characters and colours intertwined between the words, those are Markdown shortcuts which tell Ghost what to do with the words in your document. The biggest benefit of Markdown is that you can quickly apply formatting as you type, without needing to pause. At the bottom of the editor, you'll find a toolbar with basic formatting options to help you get started as easily as possible. You'll also notice that there's a ? icon, which contains more advanced shortcuts. For now, though, let's run you through some of the basics. You'll want to make sure you're editing this post in order to see all the Markdown we've used. Formatting text The most common shortcuts are of course, bold text, italic text, and hyperlinks. These generally make up the bulk of any document. You can type the characters out, but you can also use keyboard shortcuts. CMD/Ctrl + B for Bold CMD/Ctrl + I for Italic CMD/Ctrl + K for a Link CMD/Ctrl + H for a Heading (Press multiple times for h2/h3/h4/etc) With just a couple of extra characters here and there, you're well on your way to creating a beautifully formatted story. Inserting images Images in Markdown look just the same as links, except they're prefixed with an exclamation mark, like this: ![Image description](/path/to/image.jpg) Most Markdown editors don't make you type this out, though. In Ghost you can click on the image icon in the toolbar at the bottom of the editor, or you can just click and drag an image from your desktop directly into the editor. Both will upload the image for you and generate the appropriate Markdown. Important Note: Ghost does not currently have automatic image resizing, so it's always a good idea to make sure your images aren't gigantic files before uploading them to Ghost. Making lists Lists in HTML are a formatting nightmare, but in Markdown they become an absolute breeze with just a couple of characters and a bit of smart automation. For numbered lists, just write out the numbers. For bullet lists, just use * or - or +. Like this: Crack the eggs over a bowl Whisk them together Make an omellete or Remember to buy milk Feed the cat Come up with idea for next story Adding quotes When you want to pull out a particularly good except in the middle of a piece, you can use &amp;gt; at the beginning of a paragraph to turn it into a Blockquote. You might've seen this formatting before in email clients. A well placed quote guides a reader through a story, helping them to understand the most important points being made All themes handles blockquotes slightly differently. Sometimes they'll look better kept shorter, while other times you can quote fairly hefty amounts of text and get away with it. Generally, the safest option is to use blockquotes sparingly. Dividing things up If you're writing a piece in parts and you just feel like you need to divide a couple of sections distinctly from each other, a horizontal rule might be just what you need. Dropping --- on a new line will create a sleak divider, anywhere you want it. This should get you going with the vast majority of what you need to do in the editor, but if you're still curious about more advanced tips then check out the Advanced Markdown Guide - or if you'd rather learn about how Ghost taxononomies work, we've got a overview of how to use Ghost tags.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Organising your content with tags</title><link href="/using-tags" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organising your content with tags" /><published>2017-07-27T11:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T11:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/using-tags</id><content type="html" xml:base="/using-tags">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mirshad Makeen</name></author><category term="Artificial intelligence" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags. It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content. Basic tagging When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with News and other posts with Cycling, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on /tag/news/ and /tag/cycling/, respectively. If you tag a post with both News and Cycling - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data. The primary tag Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important. News, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports In this example, News is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives. Private tags Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling. For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do. News, Cycling, #video Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News, and Cycling - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting: {{#post}} {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}} ...markup for a nice big video post layout... {{else}} ...regular markup for a post... {{/has}} {{/post}} You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive theme documentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Managing Ghost users</title><link href="/managing-users" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Managing Ghost users" /><published>2017-07-27T10:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2017-07-27T10:00:00+03:00</updated><id>/managing-users</id><content type="html" xml:base="/managing-users">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;authors&quot;&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are &lt;strong&gt;trusted&lt;/strong&gt; users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;editors&quot;&gt;Editors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;administrators&quot;&gt;Administrators&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;theowner&quot;&gt;The Owner&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Mirshad Makeen</name></author><category term="gaming" /><summary type="html">Ghost has a number of different user roles for your team Authors The base user level in Ghost is an author. Authors can write posts, edit their own posts, and publish their own posts. Authors are trusted users. If you don't trust users to be allowed to publish their own posts, you shouldn't invite them to Ghost admin. Editors Editors are the 2nd user level in Ghost. Editors can do everything that an Author can do, but they can also edit and publish the posts of others - as well as their own. Editors can also invite new authors to the site. Administrators The top user level in Ghost is Administrator. Again, administrators can do everything that Authors and Editors can do, but they can also edit all site settings and data, not just content. Additionally, administrators have full access to invite, manage or remove any other user of the site. The Owner There is only ever one owner of a Ghost site. The owner is a special user which has all the same permissions as an Administrator, but with two exceptions: The Owner can never be deleted. And in some circumstances the owner will have access to additional special settings if applicable — for example, billing details, if using Ghost(Pro). It's a good idea to ask all of your users to fill out their user profiles, including bio and social links. These will populate rich structured data for posts and generally create more opportunities for themes to fully populate their design.</summary></entry></feed>