<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/artificial-intelligence/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2018-10-04T07:49:04+00:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/artificial-intelligence/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">techlanka.lk | எளிய தமிழில் தொழிநுட்ப செய்திகள் | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Latest Technology based news in Tamil</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">அலெக்சாவுடன் தமிழில் பேசலாம்! தமிழ் மொழியில் Amazon Alexa</title>
      <link href="/alexa-in-tamil" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="அலெக்சாவுடன் தமிழில் பேசலாம்! தமிழ் மொழியில் Amazon Alexa" />
      <published>2018-09-18T10:40:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2018-09-18T10:40:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/alexa-in-tamil</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/alexa-in-tamil">&lt;p&gt;Alexa gets new skills and now customers in India can help Alexa learn Tamil, Hindi, and other Indian languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;அமேசான் நிறுவனத்தின் மெய்நிகர் உதவியாளரான‌ அலெக்சாவால் இனி தமிழ் மொழியிலும் பதிலளிக்க‌ முடியும். இனி முதல் இந்திய வாடிக்கையாளர்கள், அலெக்சா (Amazon’s digital assistant Alexa) பயன்படுத்தி பல்வேறு இந்திய மொழிகளில் பேச்சு பரிமாற்றம் செய்ய‌ முடியும் என்று தெரிவிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. செயற்கை அறிவுத்திறனுடன் (artificial intelligence) இயங்கும் அலெக்சா, தற்பொழுது ஆங்கிலத்தில் மட்டுமே பயனர்களுடன் பேச்சில் ஈடுபடுகிறது. ஆப்பிள் இன் சிரி மற்றும் கூகிள் அசிஸ்டண்ட் (Apple’s Siri and Google Assistant) போன்ற மெய்நிகர் உதவியாளர்களுக்கு (virtual assistants ) நிகராக‌ உள்ளது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;தற்போது அமேசான் நிறுவனம், அலெக்சா இன் பேச்சு அறிதலினை மேம்படுத்தும் விதமாய் சில இந்திய மொழிகளில் அலெக்சாவை பயன்படுத்த முடியும் எனும் ஒரு புதிய திறனையும் சேர்த்துள்ளது. குறிப்பாக celo (கிளியோ) தொழில்நுட்பத்தின் கீழ் இந்த அமேசான் அலெக்சாவைப் பயன்படுத்த முடியும். கிளியோ தொழில்நுட்பம், மொழியியலாளர்கள் மற்றும் தரவு விஞ்ஞானிகள் கொண்ட‌ ஒரு குழுவால் வடினமைக்கப்பட்டது. இக்குழு ஏற்கனவே பிரஞ்சு மொழியினை அலெக்சா புரிதலுக்காக‌ மேம்படுத்த உதவியுள்ளது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;மேலும் இந்த அலெக்சா 2017-துவகத்தில், ஆங்கிலம் மட்டுமே புரிந்துதவும் கருவியாக‌ அமெரிக்காவில் அறிமுகம் செய்யப்பட்டது. தற்சமயம் தழிழ், இந்தி, கன்னடம், பெங்காலி, மராட்டி, குஜராத்தி, தெலுங்கு போன்ற மொழிகளில் அறிமுகம் செய்யப்பட்டுள்ளது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;அமேசான் எக்கோ (Amazon Echo) ஸ்பீக்கர்கள் மட்டுமின்றி பல மின்னணு சாதனங்களின் துணைகொண்டு குறிப்பிடப்பட்ட மொழிகளில் நீங்கள் அலெக்சாவுடன் மிக எளிமையாக பேச முடியும்.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இப்போது அறிமுகம் செய்யப்பட்ட‌ இந்த புதிய திறனை ஆக்டிவேட் செய்ய அமேசான் எக்கோ ஸ்பீக்கரிடம் அலெக்ஸா ஒப்பன் க்ளியோ (Alexa, open Cleo ) என்று குரல் கட்டளையிட்டால் போதும். பின்பு ஏதேனும் ஒரு மொழியைக் கூறி அதனுடன் மிக எளிமையாக பேசமுடியும்.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Mirshad Makeen</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Artificial intelligence" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Alexa gets new skills and now customers in India can help Alexa learn Tamil, Hindi, and other Indian languages.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Organising your content with tags</title>
      <link href="/using-tags" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organising your content with tags" />
      <published>2017-07-27T08:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-27T08:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/using-tags</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/using-tags">&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;{{#post}}
    {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}}
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    {{else}}
        ...regular markup for a post...
    {{/has}}
{{/post}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive &lt;a href=&quot;https://themes.ghost.org/&quot;&gt;theme documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Mirshad Makeen</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Artificial intelligence" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags. It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content. Basic tagging When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with News and other posts with Cycling, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on /tag/news/ and /tag/cycling/, respectively. If you tag a post with both News and Cycling - then it appears in both sections. Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data. The primary tag Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important. News, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports In this example, News is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives. Private tags Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling. For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do. News, Cycling, #video Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of News, and Cycling - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with #video. In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting: {{#post}} {{#has tag=&amp;quot;#video&amp;quot;}} ...markup for a nice big video post layout... {{else}} ...regular markup for a post... {{/has}} {{/post}} You can find documentation for theme development techniques like this and many more over on Ghost's extensive theme documentation.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
