<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/tag/software/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2018-10-02T13:08:09+03:00</updated>
  <id>/tag/software/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">techlanka.lk | எளிய தமிழில் தொழிநுட்ப செய்திகள் | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Tamil Blog for Latest Technology News</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">இன்டெல் 9வது ஜென். புரோஸசர்கள் (9th generation processors) அக்டோபரில் அறிமுகம்.</title>
      <link href="/launching-9th-generation-processors" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="இன்டெல் 9வது ஜென். புரோஸசர்கள் (9th generation processors) அக்டோபரில் அறிமுகம்." />
      <published>2018-09-18T13:18:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2018-09-18T13:18:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>/launching-9th-generation-processors</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/launching-9th-generation-processors">&lt;p&gt;Intel launching its 9th generation processors - new Core i9, i7 and i5 processors on October 1st with 8 cores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இன்டெல் நிறுவத்தின், 8 கோர்களால் ஆன‌ புதிய புரோஸசர்களான‌ கோர் i9, i7 மற்றும் i5 (new Core i9, i7 and i5 processors on October 1st with 8 cores) அக்டோபர் 1 ஆம் தேதி அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட‌ உள்ளன‌. இவை அனைத்தும் 9வது தலைமுறை புரோசசர்களாக‌ வெளியாகவுள்ளன.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;இன்டெல் கோர் i9-9900K, 8 கோர்களையும் 16 இழையுடனும் (Intel Core i9-9900K with 8 cores and 16 threads) அறிமுகம் செய்யப்படுகிறது. இணைய‌ தகவல்களின்படி, கோர் i9-9900K, கோர் ஐ9 (தொடரில்) பிராண்டின் கீழ் வெளியாகும் முதல் பிரதான‌ டெஸ்க்டாப் புரோஸசராக‌ (Core i9-9900K will be the first mainstream desktop processor) இருக்கும். இதில் முதன் முறையாக 16MB கொள்ளளவுடைய மூன்றாம் நிலை பதுக்கு நினைவகமும் (L3 Cache Memory) உள்ளடக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Core i7-9700K புரோஸசர் எட்டு கோர்கள் கொண்ட‌ (8 Core) முதல் பிரதான வகை புரோஸசராகும். இதன் வேகமானது 3.6 GHz முதல் 4.9 GHz வரை ஊக்கமளிக்கும் ஆற்றலைக் கொண்டது.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;எதிர்வரும் 9000 தொடர் இன்டெல் புரோஸசர்கள் ஏற்கனவே இருக்கும் Z3xx தொடர் மதர்போர்டுகளுடன் இணக்கமாக இருப்பதை பல மதர்போர்டு விற்பனையாளர்கள் உறுதிப்படுத்தியுள்ளனர் என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்கது.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Imran Yaseen</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="software" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Intel launching its 9th generation processors - new Core i9, i7 and i5 processors on October 1st with 8 cores.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Configure Unicenta oPOS with MySQL Database Server.</title>
      <link href="/configuring-unicenta-pos-mysql-database" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configure Unicenta oPOS with MySQL Database Server." />
      <published>2018-09-10T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2018-09-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>/configuring-unicenta-pos-mysql-database</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/configuring-unicenta-pos-mysql-database">&lt;h2 id=&quot;unicentas-default-configuration-when-freshly-installed-is-set-to-use-the-derby-database-server-a-database-server-embedded-inside-of-unicenta-this-is-only-good-for-testing-and-experimental-purposes-but-when-youre-ready-to-deploy-your-unicenta-box-you-should-be-using-it-with-an-external-database-server-like-mysql&quot;&gt;Unicenta’s default configuration when freshly installed is set to use the Derby Database Server. A database server embedded inside of Unicenta. This is only good for testing and experimental purposes. But when you’re ready to deploy your Unicenta box, you should be using it with an external Database Server like MySQL.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guide to Unicenta oPOS, that will teach how you would configure or set it up with a MySQL Database Server on MS Windows. It’s a very easy to follow guide and all procedures are written step-by-step with reference images. So if you’re looking for such guide, then jump in to read the rest of the tutorial. You could use this guide for Windows or Linux based installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the main purpose of this guide is to configure Unicenta with MySQL Database Server.
With this kind of setup, your Unicenta terminal should be able to access the database server whether it be online based server or locally deployed within your premises.
The advantages of this are; You have a separate database server where you store all your data and keep them safe in case your Unicenta box or terminal crashed or broke, you could also reinstall Unicenta for as many as you want while keeping your data safe and maintained from the database server, you could setup a multiple Unicenta terminal while maintaining a single database server which unify all your data and configurations and no need for a separate server for each terminal, you could also use a remote or online MySQL database server and connect any Unicenta terminal from different parts of the world and unify them using a single instance of database server, you as ADMIN could remotely login to Unicenta and check transaction logs, total sales and other managerial functions for a store or restaurant.
So for this guide, you’ll be taking advantage of those mentioned above after you successfully configured the MySQL database with Unicenta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To follow this guide, you must have the following.
Requirements
These are the things you need before starting off with this guide.
An instance of Unicenta installation
A separate machine/computer if you want a separate database server.
USB Web Server software for Windows based database server (if you want to use. Windows)
MySQL and LAMP Stack
PuTTy if using Windows for configuration
Some knowledge of Linux
A lot of patience
Note: I’ll be using DB and DBS here to refer to Database and Database Server.
Installation Options
There are different options and setups to configure a Database Server with your POS System.
Some options are:
Option 1 – DBS on the same machine where Unicenta is installed.
Option 2 – DBS on another separate or dedicated machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Option 1: MySQL DBS and Unicenta on the same computer.
Before you start with the initial step, make sure that you already have a working Unicenta instance.
Windows Based
In this part of the guide, we’ll configure a MySQL DBS for a Windows-based Unicenta terminal.
Both Unicenta and MySQL are on the same Windows machine.
Procedures
Step 1 – Download, extract and run USBWebserver.
You know why I recommend this portable software? It’s because I’ve already tried and tested it and had used it several times for test purposes.
But if we’re talking about multiple nodes or terminals, we should use a dedicated machine for the DBS.
To continue, just download the software, extract it to a permanent directory of your choice. Say for instance, Drive D or any drive partition other than drive C:.
Step 2 – Run the software.
Since this software is a portable server, you don’t have to configure or install any additional software, just run it.
Click on the the usbwebserver.exe file, the software should launch.
Now choose your preferred language from the drop-down menu and click OK to continue.
You should see the dashboard now.
Reference Image: USBWebserver Dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Step 3 – Configure MySQL Port.
You may or may not configure this further. But with this software, MySQL is bound to listen to port: 3307 whereas MySQL’s default listening port is 3306.
If you want to change it back to the default port, then configure it from the dashboard.
Click on Settings tab and then change port number under Port MySQL field.
Click save button.
Step 4 – Create a database for Unicenta.
Launch PHPMyAdmin using the dashboard, you could click on the the button or directly access the page using your favorite browser (Firefox or Chrome).
To access the page using a browser, browse to:
http://localhost:8080/phpmyadmin/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then login using root as the username while usbw for the password. You should see a page similar to this image.
Click on Databases menu to create a new DB for Unicenta. Enter a DB name under the Create database field, and then click on the create button. You should now have a DB for your POS. See reference image here.
Now let’s create a new user for the DB. The easiest way to do this is to create a new user with the same name as the DB name.
Click on User from the top navigation menu, then click on the Add user text link. A new page should open, now fill-up the following fields like so.
User Name – unicenta
Host – localhost
Password – your-password
NOTE: if you wanted to have a stronger password, use the Generate password button to create a longer and difficult password. When you click on the button, it will automatically fill the password field, plus it will show you the generated password on a separate field. You should copy and save this password and keep it somewhere safe.
Let’s continue, browse a further down and click/tick:
Create database with same name and grant all privileges
Grant all privileges on wildcard name
Then click Check All text link for the Global Privileges to select all options under this. Finally, click Go button from the bottom-right of the page.
And that’s it! You’ve created a Database for Unicenta. The next step would be to configure Unicenta to connect to the server.
Step 5 – Connect Unicenta to the DBS.
Go to the folder where Unicenta is installed, and then find and click the file configure.bat.
A configuration screen should pop-up like the one shown in this image.
Configure the settings like so;
From the Database dropdown menu, choose MySQL.
For the URL, jdbc:mysql://localhost:3306/unicenta
For User, unicenta
For Passwrd, your-password
Now, click the Test button to test your connection. If all is well, then you should receive a You’re Connected! pop-up message. Reference image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click OK and then finally save the settings. You’re now ready to launch and connect Unicenta to your database.
Step 6 – Fire up Unicenta.
Click on your shortcut to open Unicenta, a pop-up notice saying…
A working database cannot be detected. 
A default database will be created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to continue?
This is not an error, but a notice. It’s just natural that your newly created DB has no tables yet. So you need to hit Continue to create the tables.
Once you clicked OK you should be redirected to your Unicenta screen. If you’ve gotten this far, then congratulations you did it!&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Mirshad Makeen</name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="softwares" />
      

      
        <category term="software" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Unicenta’s default configuration when freshly installed is set to use the Derby Database Server. A database server embedded inside of Unicenta. This is only good for testing and experimental purposes. But when you’re ready to deploy your Unicenta box, you should be using it with an external Database Server like MySQL. Guide to Unicenta oPOS, that will teach how you would configure or set it up with a MySQL Database Server on MS Windows. It’s a very easy to follow guide and all procedures are written step-by-step with reference images. So if you’re looking for such guide, then jump in to read the rest of the tutorial. You could use this guide for Windows or Linux based installation.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
